SUMMARY

Full-Stack Software Engineer (JavaScript/Python + Ruby Expert) specializing in both server-side and client-side JavaScript and Python, Ruby frameworks such as React, Vue in frontend, Node.js, Django, Ruby on Rails in backend. With over 7 years of professional experience, I have had the opportunity to work on projects that run the gambit from financial platforms, to private business enterprise web applications, to building websites for digital marketing agencies, to working entrepreneurially as a freelance consultant and looking forward to contributing to build the future of the web with my next employer.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE

Sep 2011 - Nov 2015

University of Waterloo, Computer Science Waterloo, ON, Canada

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack Web Engineer (React + Node.js / Django)

Labrys, REMOTE / May 2020 - NOW

Tech Skills: React, Vue, TypeScript, Quasar, Node.js, Nest.js Python, Django, Flask, CircleCl. AWS. Docker

- Optimized and improved the code quality by owning the rewriting of the client application from an MVC view-based approach to a SPA and upgraded to React 16.8, rewriting all class-based components to functional components with hooks, implemented the Context API for global storage.
- Integrated payment services to financial platforms with Quickbooks, Freshbooks and Stripe.
- Owned the client application development for the community management and implemented with TypeScript, Vue3, Quasar and Vite.
- Wrote the CI/CD script with CircleCI, Docker and deployed application on AWS and Heroku using services.
- Came into an existing monolithic app migration from Python 2.x, Flask to Python 3.x, Django and helped speed up future schema migrations by writing SQL scripts.
- Architected and implemented microservice system based on Node.js with Nest.js, Prisma, TypeScript and PostgreSQL and authored unit tests for endpoints and functions.

Full-Stack Web Engineer (React + RoR)

MixBytes, REMOTE / Apr 2019 - Nov 2019

Tech Skills: React, TypeScript, Ruby, RoR, Jest, Enzyme, PostgreSQL

- Led the frontend development during a redesign of the internal SharePoint intranet for employees about organizational news, events, and other important information.
- Optimized and reduced the time and stress for content creators within the organization by planning, developing and launching an internal tool for creating custom SharePoint content, catered to the site.
- Architected, developed endpoints for monolith web application with Ruby, RoR and PostgreSQL
- Built frontend application for different services with React, Redux and TypeScript.



SHANE **LEWIS**

SENIOR FULL STACK ENGINEER

_

CONTACT

shanelewix@gmail.com 335 Dunsdon St., Brantford, ON, Canada

SOFT SKILLS

Flexibility
Communication
Collaboration
Creativity
Efficiency
Accountability
Self-Innovation
Self-Starter
Critical-Thinking
Problem-Solving

LANGUAGES

JavaScript 8 years
TypeScript 5 years
Python 5 years
Solidity 4 years
Ruby 3 years
Rust 3 years
Golang 2 years

WORK EXPERIENCE

- Ushered in and implemented a testing strategy in Jest and Enzyme, resulting in a test coverage of 78% of all client code.
- Supported migrating microservices and features from Python to Node.js with Nest.js, TypeORM, PostgreSQL.

Front-End Developer

Unicsoft, New York, NY / Feb 2018 - Jun 2020

Tech Skills: React, Next.js, Gatsby, TypeScript, SEO, Enzyme, React Testing Library, React Hooks, React Context, Tailwind CSS, Material UI, SASS/LESS, Figma

- Dramatically improved the user experience for over 10,000 users by optimizing client code and refactoring the web app with jQuery to using React and Redux.
- Brought in shipping confidence for the app and improved the deployment pipeline by implementing a testing harness in Jest and Enzyme covering over 75% of the code configuring linting with ESLint and formatting with Prettier for overall code quality.
- Built public web application for digital marketing agency with Next.js, improving SEO and ranking to increase page views.
- Supported migrating the codebase from class components to functional components with modern React features and libraries including React hooks and React context.

Full-Stack (FE-Heavy) Developer

MerixStudio, New York, NY / Dec 2015 - Apr 2018

Tech Skills: React, Node.js, Next.js, Gatsby, Express.js, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Apollo/GraphQL Tailwind CSS, Ant Design, D3.js, Webpack, Vite

- Designed, developed and deployed full-stack web applications according to business objectives and needs of various clients with React, Express.js, MySQL, PostgreSQL and MongoDB.
- Improved the page speed by 17% for the ecommerce site that generates \$21M
 annually in revenue by implementing Code-Splitting and Optimizing performance with
 React, GraphQL and Apollo.
- Implemented SEO in React application for e-commerce site with a catalog of 20000+ products leading to an increase in page views per session of 23% with SSR in Next.js and Gatsby.
- Built Progressive Web Application (PWA) with React, TypeScript and GraphQL (Relay).
- Worked on building customer-facing web application with Express.js, Prisma, React, PostgreSQL and Node.js.

CERTIFICATIONS

CERTIFIED WEB PROFESSIONAL

CIW, Jun 2018



SHANE **LEWIS**

SENIOR BLOCKCHAIN ENGINEER

-

FRAMEWORKS

React	7 years
Vue	5 years
Node.js	5 years
Express.js	5 years
Nest.js	4 years
Django	4 years
Flask	3 years
Ruby on Rails	3 years
Golang	3 years
Hardhat	2 years

EXTRA

MySQL
PostgreSQL
MongoDB
GraphQL(Apollo, Relay)
Next.js
Gatsby
Nuxt.js
Quasar
Laravel
Redis
Elastic Search
Docker
AWS
Vercel